Another way that things happens is, as the child ages, they obviously start to fall a lot.
As they learn to walk, as they crawl, and things of that nature.
They're falling and bumping into things, and doing all things that kids do.
In fact, some one study, I think a survey showed that the average child falls about twenty five hundred times before they're five years old.
Now, I know I'm way above average, cause I know I fell way more than twenty five hundred times before I was five years old.
Now, another thing that happens as we age, is that, we go into youth sports.
Not only youth sports but all kinds of other activities.
We've got soccer.
We've got football.
We've got baseball.
We've got gymnastics.
We've got ballet.
We've got dance.
All this going on, when bodies aren't quite ready yet to handle the physical load that's being placed upon them.
It's these little bumps, these little bruises, these little chronic, repetitive type motions, that can actually create problems within the spine.
Now, you ask why does a child need to be checked?
One thing, that I've told parents through out my chiropractic career is that as the twig is bent, so grows the tree.
If a child has a mis-alignment at an early age, there's a good possibility that that misalignment can grow into bigger things as that child ages.
It's much more effective to get that child taken of when they're young, as opposed to waiting for it to be a problem.
So, I would encourage you all to get your children checked by a chiropractor today.